<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>B L O G</title><description>Thoughts, stories and ideas about web development.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><image><url>http://localhost:2368/favicon.png</url><title>B L O G</title><link>http://localhost:2368/</link></image><generator>Ghost 1.24</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 11:21:01 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Programming and the concept of SELF</title><description>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This week I went to an exhibition at the Hayward Gallery, they were showing a retrospective of Korean artist Lee Bul's work. The work in the last room was called Via Negativa, which consisted of a maze of fragmented mirrors leading to a central room with an infinity mirror chamber,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/learning-how-to-write-in-sql/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b55c09549b06d4dcab52644</guid><dc:creator>Ritz Wu</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 11:49:45 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;div class="kg-card-markdown"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This week I went to an exhibition at the Hayward Gallery, they were showing a retrospective of Korean artist Lee Bul's work. The work in the last room was called Via Negativa, which consisted of a maze of fragmented mirrors leading to a central room with an infinity mirror chamber, surrounded by lights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2018/07/via-negativa.jpg" alt="via-negativa"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
People really did like taking selfies in this work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The outside of the structure is pages printed in reverse of Julian Jaynes' 'The origin of consciousness.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Originally, humans thought that self-consciousness was either their own thought, or the voice of God. As people’s lives began to get more complicated, the two territories have become connected and, while going back and forth between the two self-consciousnesses, we look and review [the ways in which] our selves come about.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reviewing more of Jaynes' work, which in one instance posited that humans did not gain self consciousness until the 18th century, my partner (who had come with me) had pointed out that the philosophical underpinnings of the work were so archaic to be aesthetic at best and lazy at worst. But it had me thinking about the idea of self awareness and the self as an object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In computer programming, in various languages, this, self, and Me are keywords used to refer to the object, class, or other entity of which the code is part. It is a key concept within object-oriented programming and a unique instance in which the syntax of code resembles, for an instant, to create a self-aware person or object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>